Have an account? [Sign in](https://www.autismdate.com/login)

English

Privacy Policy

IF YOU DO NOT ACCEPT AND AGREE WITH OUR PRIVACY POLICY THEN YOU MUST NOT ACCESS OR USE THE SITE AND/OR THE APPLICATION.

1\. Autism Date users and visitors to our site

What information does Autism Date collect if I decide to join the Autism Date social community?

Complete our online registration form, where we ask you to provide us with information about you such as your name, your email address, your gender, your date of birth, your location details. You also have the opportunity to provide other details about yourself, but these are optional. Because you control your user profile, these details are available to you at any time by accessing your “Profile” page, which gives you the chance to correct or update (other than gender and email address) your information at any time by just logging in to Autism Date.

Once you have created a Profile, we will automatically track certain information such as your IP and email addresses.

What information does Autism Date collect about me if I’m under 18?

You can only become a member of Autism Date if your aged 18 or over or the age of majority in the country in which you reside if that happens to be greater than 18. That means Autism Date does not knowingly collect any information about children, minors or anyone under the age of majority. Nor do we knowingly market to children, minors or anyone under the age of 18. If you are less than 18 years old, we request that you do not submit information to us. If we become aware that a child, minor or anyone under the age of 18 has registered with us and provided us with personal information, we will take steps to terminate that person’s registration and delete their Profile information from Autism Date. If we do delete a Profile because you violated our no children rules, we may retain your email and IP address to ensure that you do not try to get around our rules by creating a new Profile.

Does Autism Date collect my personal information if I am not a member and just visit the site?

No. We don’t collect any personal information about visitors to our site. If you do visit us without becoming a member, we will place session ID cookies on your computer. For more information about cookies generally, look at the answer to “How does Autism Date collect information about me?” below.

If I put other information about me on the site, what does Autism Date do with it?

Autism Date is designed to make it easy for you to find, connect and interact with other members of Autism Date by posting information about yourself. When using the App you should assume that anything you post or submit will be publicly viewable and accessible, both by Users of the App and non-Users of the App. You can also use our electronic messaging system, which allows you to communicate with other users. We recommend and encourage you (and all our members) to think carefully about the information they disclose about themselves. We also do not recommend that you put email addresses, URLs, instant messaging details, phone numbers, full names or addresses, credit card details, national identity numbers, drivers’ licence details and other sensitive information in your Profile which is open to abuse and misuse.

Please be careful about posting sensitive details about yourself on you Profile such as your religious denomination and health details. While you may voluntarily provide this information to us when you create your Profile, including your sexual preferences and ethnic background, there is no requirement to do so. Please remember that photographs or any video clips that you post on Autism Date may reveal these kinds of sensitive personal data. Where you do upload and choose to tell us sensitive information about yourself, you are explicitly consenting to our processing your information and making this public to other users.

When you post information about yourself or use the messaging, the amount of personal information you share is at your own risk.

What does Autism Date collect about me if I use the mobile app?

Autism Date offers you the opportunity to stay in touch with the friends and contacts you’ve made no matter where you are. You can do this by using your mobile phone or by downloading an application to your desktop that allows you to share your location with other users.

When you use your mobile or the desktop application, we will collect information about WiFi access points as well as other location information about your longitude and latitude. That information helps us identify your physical location so that it can be displayed and shared with other members choosing to view “nearby” posts.

If you do not want your location to be known, then please do not download the desktop application or use your mobile device when you are on Autism Date.

What’s collected from me if I use Autism Date’s premium services?

When you take advantage of Autism Date’s premium features, we collect financial information necessary to process your payments as per your chosen payment method. Please note that we do not store any credit card or other payment card details. However, our payment service providers do (and are approved to do so by all applicable regulatory bodies).

When you access Autism Date or play our games we collect certain technical information about your computer system or mobile device and statistical data about how you play our games. We use this information to improve our site and our games, so that you can increase your fun.

Can Autism Date collect information about me from other sites I use, such as Facebook?

If you have registered on one of our partner websites, such as Facebook, your Profile will be available to all users of the Autism Date social network whether via our site or our partners’ websites.

Remember that when you register with a Autism Date partner, you are also giving them personal information, so we recommend that you read their privacy policies as Autism Date does not control how they use their information.

If you have have registered on one of our partner websites, such as Facebook, or you have verified your account via a partner website, we may connect your Autism Date profile with your profile on such partner website. We may do this by way of new products and applications which we introduce from time to time, including new products powered by our group companies.

If you have verified your account through a partner website and do not want to link your Autism Date profile to your profile on the partner website, please go to the “Verifications” section on your profile page and click “forget this account”.

If you have created a Autism Date profile through a partner website and you do not want to link your Autism Date profile to your profile on the partner website, Autism Date cannot amend these settings. Please visit the application settings on your partner website profile and follow the instructions to remove the Autism Date access permissions.

Does Autism Date collect any other personal information about me?

If you contact our Customer Support team via [\[email protected\]](https://www.autismdate.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), we will receive your email address, and may track your IP address as well as the information you send to us to help resolve your query. We will keep records of our communications with you, including any complaints that we receive from you about other users (and from other users about you).

Will Autism Date contact me?

On your “Settings” page Autism Date offers you the opportunity to receive emails from us about new message notifications or other purposes related to the use of the website.

Does Autism Date use my personal information for any other purpose?

We may use material that you post on the open access areas of Autism Date in advertising and promotional materials on our partner sites and partner products. We believe these uses allow us to improve our site and better tailor your online experience to meet your needs.

We use your personal information to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our Terms of Use.

What are 'cookies' and what 'cookies' does Autism Date use?

We collect information by placing cookies on your computer or mobile. A cookie is a piece of text stored on your computer or mobile by your web browser. They are basically a tool that stores information about website visits, recognises you and your preferences each time you visit Autism Date, and ensures site functionality and enables us to provide the services our members request.

When you visit the publicly available sections of Autism Date, a session ID cookie is placed on your computer that only lasts while you’re visiting. We also place persistent cookies (also known an local storage devices) on members’ computers, so that Autism Date remembers them and makes their login experience faster and easier. We may use persistent tracking cookies on your mobile device, mainly for security protection purposes, such as to prevent phishers, scammers, unauthorised log in attempts, and to help you access your hacked account. We do not use any information whilst you are logged off.

You may set your browser and your mobile settings to block cookies and local storage devices, but if you do so, you may not be able to access the features that Autism Date offers.

Autism Date uses cookies and local storage devices for a number of reasons, including to ensure the security of our site, to provide you with features you have requested and to analyse how members and visitors use Autism Date. Autism Date’s uses of cookies and local shared devices so that we know who you are, what interests you and so that you can do the things online that you want to do, like chat with new people, share your content and buy Super Powers knowing that your data will be secure. Our use of cookies and local share devices, including the specific cookie names, may change over time, but will generally fall into the above categories. Please visit this page regularly so that you are aware of any changes.

If you would like to know more about cookies, including flash cookies/local storage devices, the following websites provide useful information:

* [http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html](http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html)

2\. Friends and other Autism Date users

When I put information about myself on Autism Date, what do the other users see?

To ensure you get to meet as many people as possible on Autism Date, other members get to see your user name and any information you post on your Profile, including photos if you select the 'Any users' access setting. Any information you choose to provide should reflect how much you want other Autism Date members to know about you. You can also choose to limit the information that other users see by adjusting your privacy settings in the “Settings” page.

What am I allowed to do with other user’s personal information?

Use it to meet new friends and make new contacts! Beware that you may not use other users' information for commercial purposes, to spam, to harass, or to make unlawful threats. Autism Date reserves the right to terminate the accounts of those who misuse other users' information.

What information does Autism Date collect about my friends and contacts?

You can choose to invite your friends to join Autism Date to make sure that they also get the benefits of meeting new people. To make it easier to search and find friends and acquaintances on Autism Date, users may search for other members by email address. If you want to invite your friends and contacts to Autism Date, we will send an email invitation from Autism Date in your name or you can send an SMS (if you use our Android or iPhone app) to your friends and contacts encouraging them to sign up to Autism Date. If any of the individuals you have invited do not register within a few days, Autism Date may occasionally send reminder emails on your behalf to those individuals. You can choose to invite all your friends or only a select few by simply unticking the names of those friends you do not wish to invite, but please remember you must not invite any children to join. You are responsible for ensuring that your friend has agreed to receiving a Autism Date invite.

When you import your contacts, we store their name and email address or their mobile number so that we can automatically connect you and your friend. Autism Date does not sell these email addresses or mobile numbers or use them to send any other communication besides email invitations. The friend may contact Autism Date to request the removal of their information from our database by clicking Contact us. Any such request will only apply to addresses or mobile numbers we have at the time of the request and not to any addresses that the member/user provides to us later.

3\. Third parties

Does Autism Date sell my information to other parties?

Not at all. We do not sell or rent out any personal information about you to any third party. Autism Date discloses aggregated non-personal data for marketing and promotional purposes. That means we do not disclose any information that could be used to identify you.

Does Autism Date disclose my information to other parties?

We may share aggregated information with such parties as Foursquare that includes your personal information (but which doesn’t identify you directly), together with other information including log data with third parties for industry analysis and demographic profiling and to deliver targeted advertising about other products and services.

In particular, in relation to targeted advertising, we use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

If you choose to, we may share your information with vendors, service providers, and other carefully selected third parties to improve our services to you, such as by facilitating payments. We ensure these parties must adhere to strict data protection and confidentiality provisions that are consistent with this Privacy Policy.

Autism Date also wishes to maintain a healthy community, and we will cooperate with all law enforcement inquiries and with all third parties to enforce their intellectual property or other rights. We may also disclose your personal information to government or law enforcement agencies, or private parties, as required by law when/or, in our sole discretion, we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our legal rights, or those of third parties and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us.

In the event that Autism Date or any of its affiliates undergoes a business transition or change of ownership, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, re-organisation, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, or in the event of insolvency or administration, we may be required to disclose your personal information.

4\. Data storage

Where is my personal information kept?

Autism Date is a global website operating through a server located in Germany. If you live in a country with data protection laws, the storage of your personal data may not provide you with the same protections as you enjoy in your country of residence. By submitting your personal information, or by choosing to upgrade the services you use, or by making use of the applications available on Autism Date, you agree to the transfer of your personal information to, and storage and processing of your personal information in this country

5\. Security

How does Autism Date protect my personal information?

Autism Date has implemented reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect and prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control, including your personal information. Autism Date uses reasonable security measures to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information such as secured servers using firewalls. Our technical experts at Autism Date work hard to ensure your secure use of our site.

While we take reasonable precautions against possible security breaches of our website, member database and records no website or Internet transmission is completely secure and we cannot guarantee that unauthorised access, hacking, data loss, or other breaches will never occur. We urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe (including your password) and to log out of your account after use.

We cannot guarantee the security of your personal data while it is being transmitted to our site and any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information we have procedures and security features in place to try to prevent unauthorised access.

How do I help keep my information secure?

You may not disclose your password to any third parties or share it with any third parties. If you lose your password or give it out, your personal information may be compromised. You must change your password immediately via your “Settings” page. Autism Date cannot be held responsible for your failure to keep your password secure.

6\. Your rights

How do I change my Profile?

You can review and revise your profile information at any time. Once you register, you will be able to review and change much of your personal information including:

1. Your contact email address;
2. Your profile, photographs, and videos;
3. Your city, region, and country of residence;
4. Your password.

Please promptly update your information if it changes by signing-in to your account and following the screen prompts. We strongly urge you to periodically change your password to help reduce the risk of unauthorised access to your account information.

Users in certain jurisdictions are, in accordance with applicable law, entitled to exercise a right of access to personal information about themselves by asking for a copy of the information we hold about them (for which, where allowed by law, we may charge a small fee).

Can I deactivate or delete my Profile?

Users of the Autism Date network have the following choices to delete their profile from our database:

1. Send a message via [\[email protected\]](https://www.autismdate.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
2. Sign in with your password and delete your profile. These options are available from your “Settings” page.

To prevent abuse and/or misuse of Autism Date by a user following termination or deletion of a profile/account we shall retain such information as we deem in our sole discretion may be necessary to ensure that user does not open a new account and profile in breach of our Terms of Use and to ensure compliance with all laws and regulations.

Warning: Even after you remove information from your profile or delete your account, copies of that information may still be viewable and/or accessed on the Internet to the extent such information has been previously shared with others, or copied or stored by other users or to the extent such information has been shared with search engines. We cannot control this, nor do we accept any liability for this. If you have given third party applications or websites access to your personal information they may retain such information to the extent permitted under their terms of service or privacy policies.

What happens if I do nothing?

If you have not signed in to Autism Date for three months, we may remove your Profile as part of our data cleansing process.

If your account is not confirmed in 30 days after registration via the confirmation email, your account will be deleted.

​Your Autism Date account is non-transferable and any rights to your profile or contents within your account will be cancelled upon your death.

If you have questions about our Privacy Policy or how we collect and use information, drop us a line via [\[email protected\]](https://www.autismdate.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 25th of december 2020.

© Autism Date 2024

Cancel Save

Edit image

Make profile picture

Comments hidden

Cancel Send

Verify your account now!

Cancel Verify
